now let's discuss the solution to a two
bit predictor quiz we have a two bit
predictor like this the question is is
there a sequence of branch outcomes such
that this predictor starting in the
strong not taken state always miss
predicts and the answer is of course yes
every single predictor has the worst
case scenario of always miss predicting
what you have to do to find out what
that worst-case scenario is is simply
design a sequence such that whatever the
state of the predictor is the sequence
goes the opposite way so we start in the
stronger taken state thus the first
decision would be taken that would take
us to a weak not taken state the
predictor would still predict not-taken
so we make the branch be taken next time
now the predictor goes to the weak taken
state and now we know how to cause the
alternation between the states so in the
weak taken state we go not taken it
moves too weak not taken now we say
taken and so on so you can just keep
doing this so pretty much even if we do
start in a strong taking state there is
a way to move us to a weak state at
which point we can do this alternation
note that for this particular sequence
there is a way to change these
predictors so that this behavior doesn't
result in 100% miss prediction but in
general every predictor no matter how
its organized will always have some
sequence as its worst possible outcome
it's just a matter of how likely is that
sequence a good predictor will not have
this worst case behavior for something
that is a very likely sequence to happen
so again every predictor has a
worst-case scenario where it's doing
100% miss predictions